# MELVIN HERNANDEZ

Chicago, IL · 312.838.1617

melher39@gmail.com · linkedin.com/in/melvin-hernandez · melher39.github.io

Full stack web developer and technology enthusiast with an entrepreneurial background and over a decade of experience diagnosing and repairing both hardware and software issues that arise in modern electronics.

# **EXPERIENCE**

**JUNE 2014 - SEPTEMBER 2018** 

## CO-OWNER / LEAD TECHNICIAN, MODERN TECH SOLUTIONS LLC, CHICAGO, IL

Operated a small business focusing on the repair of consumer electronics.

**JANUARY 2014 - MAY 2014** 

## **LEAD TECHNICIAN, SANSON COMMUNICATIONS**, WEST CHICAGO, IL

Lead and taught a team of technicians both hardware and software skills utilized in the electronics repair industry.

**MARCH 2012 - JANUARY 2014** 

MANAGER / COMPUTER TECHNICIAN, MY CLEAR TECH, CHICAGO, IL

Managed and serviced multiple electronic repair and retail stores.

# **EDUCATION**

**APRIL 2019** 

#### **FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPMENT BOOTCAMP**

## NORTHWESTERN UNIVERISTY, EVANSTON, IL

• Extensive, fast-paced 24-week program learning and applying various technologies to the design and development of modern web applications.

**DECEMBER 2011** 

## **ASSOCIATE IN ENGINEERING SCIENCE**

## WILBUR WRIGHT COLLEGE, CHICAGO, IL

- Studied engineering fundamentals through advanced math and science courses
- PTK Honor Society

# **SKILLS**

- Web Development: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, node.js, GIT, GitHub
- Debugging / Troubleshooting
- Computer Hardware

- Bilingual English & Spanish
- Smartphone Repair
- Self-Motivated
- Meticulous